<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Tatiana Mac</title>
	<subtitle>Work, writing, speaking.</subtitle>
	<link href="https://tatianamac.com/feed/rss.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://www.tatianamac.com/"/>
	<updated>2019-07-09T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
	<id>https://tatianamac.com/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Tatiana Mac</name>
		<email>inquiry@tatianamac.com</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>TRUST the Process</title>
		<link href="https://www.tatianamac.com/posts/trust-the-process/"/>
		<updated>2019-02-04T16:00:00-08:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.tatianamac.com/posts/trust-the-process/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Between the forced interactions, uncertainty, and pressure placed upon success (often our health depends upon successfully acquiring a job), job hunting is a veritable hotbed for anxiety and depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it’s safe to say that many of us enter the job hunt during difficult times, where we’re not presenting our best selves. The circumstances for our current employment/unemployment, like recent termination or forced resignation or feeling stuck in a job we hate, might contribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the cloud of negativity around this process compounds exponentially, and can further exacerbate what is already a difficult, unclear, and arduous process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing we need to “snap out” of the cycle of depression — employment (or what it brings, like independence, money, healthcare, success, etc) — is unattainable because we’re not presenting our best self. We’re unable to present our best self, because we’re depressed. The vicious cycle ensues as resources rapidly deplete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what do we do? As someone who has continually suffered from severe anxiety, depression, and suicidal tendencies, I’ve learned some ways to cope along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this juncture, I want to acknowledge that this process is. not. easy. It is perfectly normal to have “productive, good days,” and to have “wasted, bad days.” Or weeks. Or months. You are worth more than the sum of your productivity. As with coping and surviving depression, the process is far from linear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The secret is that you have to T.R.U.S.T. the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;%5Bt%5Dry-not-to-compare-yourself-to-anyone%2C-except-your-past-and-future-selves.&quot;&gt;[T]ry not to compare yourself to anyone, except your past and future selves. &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#%5Bt%5Dry-not-to-compare-yourself-to-anyone%2C-except-your-past-and-future-selves.&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is very easy to fall into a trap where you’re six pages deep into Dribbble for portfolio inspiration, instead wondering why your UIs aren’t as crisp, illustrations not as dynamic, and animations not as clever as everybody else’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, you are comparing yourself to the entire world. How is that going to work? Let’s try it out. Talented illustrator could have had access to the best tools, tutelage, and time. Chances are you’re going to fixate on all of their positives, without considering that they also come with negatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talented illustrator could also be really trash at brushing their teeth, yields incorrectly at four-way stops, and had a less evolved understanding of information architecture as you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll never know for sure. What have you gained from this exercise? Exactly nothing. What have you lost? Energy and time. When you’re depressed, energy is one of your premium resources. You need to use it wisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, comparing yourself to your past or future self. Most designers I know are constantly improving. So, if you’re comparing yourself to your past, it is likely a point of pride. Look at how far you’ve come! (I frequently look at my awkward middle school pictures side-by-side with my current photos and I’m like–dang, where’d that babe come from?!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you feel you’ve digressed? That’s okay and 100 percent normal! Improvement is not always a steady incline. Sometimes when we grow wider and more vast, our niche skills can plateau for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, if you’re depressed right now, chances are you aren’t operating at full throttle. You might be less motivated to learn, less able to retain new skills, and be in a temporary state of regression. It is okay. It is normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now as for comparing yourself to your future self, without turning this into a Christopher Nolan plot, all I can say is that you have time to formulate who you want to become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start now with your present self. Respect exactly where you are, here, right now. Accept this self in all of its imperfections. Because for every imperfection you’re accepting, you’re also accepting a whole host of accomplishments and battle wounds that are worth celebration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;%5Br%5Delinquish-control.&quot;&gt;[R]elinquish control. &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#%5Br%5Delinquish-control.&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who love control, this is a difficult one. I find that a part of what causes me to feel depressed is that I feel out of control of everything (financial wellbeing, freedom, etc), so I seek to control everything at once (at which I inevitably fail). The dichotomy causes me to feel in control of absolutely nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting caught up in cycles is a sure way to perpetuate cycles of depression. A strategy I employ is to disrupt circuitous trains of thought like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the job hunt, there are so many factors outside of your control. You can’t control most of the processes, including the speed at which recruiters respond, the selection criteria, and the implicit biases of the hiring team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can’t control even your own success. You can only do your best at that time. Remember that your best when you’re feeling down might be a lot less than when you’re at your best (hence, why it’s so critical to get caught up on comparisons).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, you do not have control over the outcome. The outcome is the result of so many other factors and dependencies (that you also don’t have control over).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lack of control can feel unnerving. When I feel unsettled by it, I remind myself that relinquishing control also means relinquishing blame and guilt. It’s not my fault if I don’t get the job. It’s okay that that interview didn’t go perfectly. (I want to note here that I’m not suggesting that we can relieve of ourselves of all responsibility for our actions. When we’re feeling more stable, we can again reframe this in a more proactive way, but when we’re not as well, I find it helpful to focus on gentler approaches like this.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;%5Bu%5Dnderstand-that-you-cannot-singularly-change-systemic-problems.&quot;&gt;[U]nderstand that you cannot singularly change systemic problems. &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#%5Bu%5Dnderstand-that-you-cannot-singularly-change-systemic-problems.&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep breath. I really struggle with this one. The complexity of job hunting as a woman of colour in tech is worthy of its own post, as it is for disabled, trans, and queer folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you represent an underrepresented, marginalised group, it’s possible you feel the burden of breaking barriers and showing up for your group. It’s a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when you’re feeling the unbearable pressure of finding a job—a hefty feat on its own—adding the burden of centuries of systemic oppression to your shoulders is not a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I say this with the world’s optimism: You cannot protect your group with a single decision you make. You do not need to be a martyr or make a stand for the greater good. Chances are, singularly, your brave act will get lost and ultimately not have the impact you want anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead heed the direction of airplane oxygen masks: Help yourself first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust me when I say that we all understand. Your fight for social justice, while very noble, requires first for you to be alive and well to do so. Do what you need to do to survive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;%5Bs%5Dee-yourself-from-your-cheering-section.&quot;&gt;[S]ee yourself from your cheering section. &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#%5Bs%5Dee-yourself-from-your-cheering-section.&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The repeated rejection inherent to job searches can do numbers on even the most stable of egos. Worthlessness, waning confidence, and uncertainty are already part of a packaged deal with depression. The self you see in the mirror, a shell of yourself, is probably not the visage you want to project to prospective employers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I’m feeling this low, I do what people tell you not to do: I fish for compliments. Find your biggest fans via email, text, Instagram DM, Twitter, FaceTime. Whatever mechanism you need, use it unabashedly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might feel awkward to ask, but you can always start with first telling that person something nice about them as a prompt. Doing so will encourage you to be in a positive mindset and help to focus on someone else for a moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;What are some positive qualities that are unique to me?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;How do I make your life better?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;What’s your fondest memory of me?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Tell me something you like about me.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answers to these questions may or may not relate directly to characteristics that are pertinent to your employability proper, but at the very least, it will remind you that you are a worthy person who has people who are rooting for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cheering section is also the place from which you want to conduct all areas of the job hunting process. Present your work to your cheering section. Ask for the compensation your cheering section thinks you deserve. Carefully weigh options as your cheering section would suggest. Face your audience of fans and turn your back to the imaginary haters. Do your fans think you deserve more than you feel you do in this place? (Most definitely, yes.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we can forget what we are capable of and what we deserve when we’re sad. We end up dodging failure instead of reaching for radical success. Our peers and loved ones are there to remind us; to cast our best mirrored selves back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;%5Bt%5Dake-one-step-at-a-time.&quot;&gt;[T]ake one step at a time. &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#%5Bt%5Dake-one-step-at-a-time.&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I consult with job hunters who are feeling depressed, I often remind them of this very simple advice. It’s one of my favourite mantras, as it works on a number of different levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many folks stress about whether or not they’ll move for the job when they haven’t even applied yet. Or, they’ll worry about whether or not they’ll take the offer before they’ve even gotten an interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The macrosteps of the job hunting process are quite broad and drawn out: deciding to apply, seeking places, applying, interviewing, receiving an offer, accepting the offer, and addressing the ways it’ll impact your life. Each of these steps is major.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I can respect the need to plan, we’ve been tricked into believing that job hunting is express train to decision town. The expedited process is a falsehood that hasty employers have created and respect only when to their advantage. (Do you ever wonder why they’re in no hurry to get you to the second or third interview? Or how hundreds of applications sit latently before ever viewed? Does it really seem like they’re in a rush to you?) In most cases, unless your job involves directly saving lives, the difference between a couple of weeks of each step is not life or death of the company. If it is, you may want to assess their planning skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in our analogy, if you get to the point of accepting the offer, you can worry/strategise how to move your entire life to Amsterdam. (And of course noting here by contrast that while it’s not life or death on the company side, that there is tremendous anxiety around a couple of weeks, as that can mean groceries in your belly and roof over your heard; life or death for you.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But until the steps prior have occurred, that kind of what-if thinking will only cause unnecessary anxiety. Worse yet, thinking this way also gets you obsessing in an alternate world where you’ve magically bypassed the necessary steps of successful application, interview, offer, and acceptance. Effectively, you’re statistically setting yourself up for disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re depressed, that can be a very detrimental thing to do for your already tender heart. Don’t make your heart deal with more than it needs to right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let’s say you’ve moved onto the interview process. First, recall what outcome you want for this step, and this step alone (I recommend for this example: Finding out if you even wanna work at this company and might get along with your colleagues!). Then, if you proceed from this step, you are under no obligation to proceed through all the rest. You can evaluate the desired outcome for those steps! Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because one step at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When crafting your portfolio, the doubt can easily sink in. The work you’ve done is irrelevant. The jobs you’ve picked are wrong. The skills you have aren’t sharp enough. So, how do you craft a portfolio out of nothing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start and anchor yourself with a singular point of joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was working on my portfolio last year, at the height of my depression, I fixated on the single illustration that floats above. I borrowed it from a previous project that I loved. I modified it until it brought me joy. I started somewhere with relatively low effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I anchored my colour palette around the illustration. I complemented my typography to it. Step by step, line by line, I found myself with a header. Then with a section. One component of work, then another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building my portfolio was slow moving. The code I wrote wasn’t perfect. Some of the components were less accessible than I knew how to make. But you know what? It was better than the years of stagnation I’d previously allowed. I relinquished control over the idea of perfection, and removed myself on being the shining example of the accessibility community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I favoured progress over perfection. I valued each small step, because it meant that no matter how slowly, I was moving forward. When you’re bedridden, barely able to motivate yourself to eat, this feat is no easy task. So it’s equally important to acknowledge these incremental steps, no matter how small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If and when you’re rejected at various steps, remember to celebrate all the steps you took to get there. A lack of offer doesn’t mean failure to find a job, it means a successful application and completed interview. The lack of offer here means a better offer is out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know, friend, that I know that none of this is easy. It’s all very hard. You will struggle as we all have. You are not alone in this. But as long as you continue to believe in yourself and trust the process, I know you will prevail, one step at a time. We’re rooting for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am always willing to answer questions about how to cope with the arduous job seeker’s journey (DM me on Twitter, email me!) And, if you’re thinking about suicide, are worried about a loved one, or would like emotional support, please call 1–800–273–8255 or visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://suicidepreventionlifeline.org/&quot;&gt;suicidepreventionlifeline.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Tired</title>
		<link href="https://www.tatianamac.com/posts/tired/"/>
		<updated>2019-04-15T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.tatianamac.com/posts/tired/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m tired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m tired of not being seen. Of having to choose to dodge or to push. Of having to subserviate myself to people who don&#39;t even acknowledge my existence. Of having to make the conscious decision to hold space— space that I am repeatedly promised, but only in theory, never in practice. I&#39;m tired of the reaction when we collide, bitterness that I didn&#39;t yield to begin with and confusion in the internalised expectation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m tired of not being viewed. Of having to choose to be seen for my gender or for my race. Of having to accommodate to Westernised standards of beauty and of being defined on binaries that never counted me as a one but as a zero. I&#39;m tired of being seen only in parts, and never in whole. A supporting actor, always.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m tired of not being heard. Of having to assert my voice to take space at work and at the bar, just to hear my words float in limbo rarely processed, rarely heard. Or in a rare instance when it is heard, it is repackaged in a larger box, with more packaging with someone else&#39;s name on it. That palatable, approachable box delivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;i&#39;m-tired-of-not-being-felt.&quot;&gt;I&#39;m tired of not being felt. &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#i&#39;m-tired-of-not-being-felt.&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of having to defend the truth my lived experiences with data and screenshots and typed out summaries of paragraphs from those who came before me who survived similar things. Just to have it all invalidated as hyperbole or as outrage. I&#39;m met with the requirement to listen to the intents and the meanings and the intents and meanings and intents and the meanings without ever being asked just once—what kind of impact that it might have had on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;i&#39;m-tired-of-not-being-valued.&quot;&gt;I&#39;m tired of not being valued. &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#i&#39;m-tired-of-not-being-valued.&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of having to repeatedly prove my worth in an industry that never conceived that I would be allowed to sit at the table. I&#39;m tired of being told that the right person will come along; that the loneliness of being single will pass from people who will return home to the comfort of their significant others. I&#39;m tired of being told that the right company will finally see my worth and will hire me, if I just hold out, from people who can expect their paycheck on Friday from their steady jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;i&#39;m-tired-of-not-being-believed.&quot;&gt;I&#39;m tired of not being believed. &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#i&#39;m-tired-of-not-being-believed.&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of having to reexplain how racism requires prejudice and power, how the microaggressions hurt differently but no less, and how yes, you, my beloved friend, were and are and continue to be capable of the most racist words and actions. And how your complicit silence hurts more than explicit slurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;i&#39;m-tired-of-not-being-trusted.&quot;&gt;I&#39;m tired of not being trusted. &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#i&#39;m-tired-of-not-being-trusted.&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of having to hear how I should or should not be feeling from people who are supposed to love me unconditionally. Of having to hear how my brown thoughts are overreactions or misconceptions in their white world. Of having to hold space for feelings as so many of us face an imminent fear of death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;i&#39;m-tired-of-living-in-a-world-of-buts-and-ors.&quot;&gt;I&#39;m tired of living in a world of buts and ors. &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#i&#39;m-tired-of-living-in-a-world-of-buts-and-ors.&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world where you win, or I win. In a world where I have to crawl on the backs of people who look like me; people who are struggling in the same and in different ways. Because my existence doesn&#39;t work that way. I exist in a world of ands and withs, being multitudes and holding opinions that seem like contradictions where more than one truth can exist—it is a world of abundance, of not only resources, but of perspectives and of truths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;i&#39;m-tired-of-the-balance.&quot;&gt;I&#39;m tired of the balance. &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#i&#39;m-tired-of-the-balance.&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of not giving up on everyone while repeatedly being beat down by disappointment. Of being cautiously optimistic as I am seared into pessimism. Of seeking love and happiness in a world that returns me so much hate and sadness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;i&#39;m-tired-of-asking%3A&quot;&gt;I&#39;m tired of asking: &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#i&#39;m-tired-of-asking%3A&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I survive in this world of mutual exclusion when what nourishes me—what might provide me a momentary meditative rest— is mutual inclusion?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Cracked</title>
		<link href="https://www.tatianamac.com/posts/cracked/"/>
		<updated>2019-04-16T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.tatianamac.com/posts/cracked/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;!-- It&#39;s dangerous because the crack never goes away. You might look past it, forget it, but it was always there to remind you that it was always going to crack. It never hid its betrayal, you just stopped looking.
--- --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Driving with a cracked windshield feels dangerous at first, especially the moments after it happens. Your instinct says to pull over, stop driving until you get a new windshield. But you get distracted and end up driving with it for longer than you want. Then after awhile, you forget how you felt when it first happened and how close you are to a potentially scary fate. At some point, the last bits of tension fail and inevitably shatter when you least expect it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day, I drive around with cracked windshields of varying depth. I never know when they will shatter. I never know how much strength they each have left. But I know they will all eventually shatter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It obstructs the view, but I learned to navigate around it. I started to find the way it refracts stop lights in the rain a bit charming, if not inconvenient at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On most days, I forget about the crack. And it&#39;s fine, those days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then it happens. The crack goes from its familiar shape to something far scarier, changing states from idle to aggressive. In that fractional moment, I remember why it&#39;s dangerous to drive with cracked windshields. It&#39;s dangerous because the crack never goes away. You might look past it, forget it, but it was always there to remind you that it was always going to crack. It never hid its betrayal, you just stopped looking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many times as they fail me, I still can&#39;t just stop driving these cars with shattered windshields. Because it&#39;s hard to get rid of your car. There&#39;s memories in the miles, it takes time and money and energy to find and to reacquaint yourself with a new car, and you want to believe it won&#39;t get worse. Perhaps there&#39;s an ignorant part of me that believes that the crack can heal itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I drive in trepidation, conscious and careful not to place any pressure on this fragile line, but in the end I know that no matter how hard I try, that I have no bearing on its shattering point. It&#39;s just a matter of time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Why beginners should teach</title>
		<link href="https://www.tatianamac.com/posts/why-beginners-should-teach/"/>
		<updated>2019-04-16T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.tatianamac.com/posts/why-beginners-should-teach/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Beginners teaching will create more empathy, combat Imposter Syndrome, and diversify industry voices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginners! I&#39;d love to see more of you &lt;em&gt;teach.&lt;/em&gt; You have tremendous value to offer. In our industry, we uphold and revere experts. I get it. Experts do sexy slick things in time lapses, have nice camera equipment, and great hair days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 reasons to do it for yourself, your future students, and your peers, and our industry as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you may be intimidated by how many tutorials already exist, you have to remember your uniqueness. People like different teaching styles, voices, EDM BG music selection. And, I&#39;m gonna guess a lot of those tutorials are taught by experts, which leads to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginners acutely feel the struggles of other beginners: confused with the onslaught of tools, terminology, and where to begin. The initial hurdle is the hardest. It&#39;s the place where quitting seems most appealing because there&#39;s an endless supply of things to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginners want to see other beginners. Representation is a very important aspect of what we do: People get intimidated when they only see experts teaching high-level things. Seeing another beginner make mistakes on &amp;quot;basic things&amp;quot; then recover is very encouraging!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More beginners teaching will also show more beginner work! It&#39;s unrealistic to expect that your first will be on par with a practised expert whose done hundreds. That&#39;s okay! Share your &amp;quot;uglies,&amp;quot; as they&#39;re probably not as bad as you think and are an impt part of the process!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More beginners will mean more forgiveness for &lt;em&gt;mistakes.&lt;/em&gt; Our society is so fearful of mistakes and the gaslighting. Totally get it. Mistakes are icky. Peeps are dix. But mistakes are a &lt;em&gt;necessary&lt;/em&gt; part of growth. So make &#39;em! Share what you &lt;em&gt;learned&lt;/em&gt; from them! Fuck haters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internalising how to teach helps you organise how to learn: Where to start, where to focus, basic terms, anticipating your students&#39; questions. For my Skillshare class, I knew I had to narrow the scope of all #a11y down to something compact enough to digest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More beginner teachers means more people doing things they love, even if they&#39;re kinda bad at it at first. For me, it&#39;s drawing. My talented friends have been drawing since the womb. I&#39;m old AF now. I have no time! So many of the hands I draw are uggo. WHO CARES. I HAD FUN!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diversifying the levels will keep experts grounded and aware of newbie hurdles. Experts become super users of languages and tools; hearing beginner teachers will help to remind them of the initial struggles and help to cater their future, more advanced tutorials accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More beginners means more humility! We hide a lot of the &amp;quot;sausage making&amp;quot; from our peers, clients, the non-design world. But what if we were more okay accepting imperfect, in-progress, new things? Perhaps imposter syndrome would be less pervasive and there&#39;d be less shame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, more beginners will inherently diversify and amplify a broader group of voices who haven&#39;t been &amp;quot;at the table&amp;quot; and advanced to experts - WoC, trans, disabled folks. Ignored and repressed voices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see you. You have value.&lt;br&gt;
Share with me your beginners teaching beginners channels and links! I&#39;ll save &#39;em and share. DM me on Twitter if you have questions on how to structure scripts, platforms to host, etc or just need to get out of your own head! You got this!!!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Why beginners should teach</title>
		<link href="https://www.tatianamac.com/posts/why-we-need-beginners-teaching/"/>
		<updated>2019-04-16T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.tatianamac.com/posts/why-we-need-beginners-teaching/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Beginners teaching will create more empathy, combat Imposter Syndrome, and diversify industry voices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginners! I&#39;d love to see more of you &lt;em&gt;teach.&lt;/em&gt; You have tremendous value to offer. In our industry, we uphold and revere experts. I get it. Experts do sexy slick things in time lapses, have nice camera equipment, and great hair days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are 10 reasons to do it for yourself, your future students, and your peers, and our industry as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you may be intimidated by how many tutorials already exist, you have to remember your uniqueness. People like different teaching styles, voices, EDM BG music selection. And, I&#39;m gonna guess a lot of those tutorials are taught by experts, which leads to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginners acutely feel the struggles of other beginners: confused with the onslaught of tools, terminology, and where to begin. The initial hurdle is the hardest. It&#39;s the place where quitting seems most appealing because there&#39;s an endless supply of things to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginners want to see other beginners. Representation is a very important aspect of what we do: People get intimidated when they only see experts teaching high-level things. Seeing another beginner make mistakes on &amp;quot;basic things&amp;quot; then recover is very encouraging!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More beginners teaching will also show more beginner work! It&#39;s unrealistic to expect that your first will be on par with a practised expert whose done hundreds. That&#39;s okay! Share your &amp;quot;uglies,&amp;quot; as they&#39;re probably not as bad as you think and are an impt part of the process!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More beginners will mean more forgiveness for &lt;em&gt;mistakes.&lt;/em&gt; Our society is so fearful of mistakes and the gaslighting. Totally get it. Mistakes are icky. Peeps are dix. But mistakes are a &lt;em&gt;necessary&lt;/em&gt; part of growth. So make &#39;em! Share what you &lt;em&gt;learned&lt;/em&gt; from them! Fuck haters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internalising how to teach helps you organise how to learn: Where to start, where to focus, basic terms, anticipating your students&#39; questions. For my Skillshare class, I knew I had to narrow the scope of all #a11y down to something compact enough to digest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More beginner teachers means more people doing things they love, even if they&#39;re kinda bad at it at first. For me, it&#39;s drawing. My talented friends have been drawing since the womb. I&#39;m old AF now. I have no time! So many of the hands I draw are uggo. WHO CARES. I HAD FUN!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diversifying the levels will keep experts grounded and aware of newbie hurdles. Experts become super users of languages and tools; hearing beginner teachers will help to remind them of the initial struggles and help to cater their future, more advanced tutorials accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More beginners means more humility! We hide a lot of the &amp;quot;sausage making&amp;quot; from our peers, clients, the non-design world. But what if we were more okay accepting imperfect, in-progress, new things? Perhaps imposter syndrome would be less pervasive and there&#39;d be less shame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, more beginners will inherently diversify and amplify a broader group of voices who haven&#39;t been &amp;quot;at the table&amp;quot; and advanced to experts - WoC, trans, disabled folks. Ignored and repressed voices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see you. You have value.&lt;br&gt;
Share with me your beginners teaching beginners channels and links! I&#39;ll save &#39;em and share. DM me on Twitter if you have questions on how to structure scripts, platforms to host, etc or just need to get out of your own head! You got this!!!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Sunday</title>
		<link href="https://www.tatianamac.com/posts/sunday/"/>
		<updated>2019-04-20T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.tatianamac.com/posts/sunday/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the surface, today was a good day. I usually tend to all my plants on Sunday; it’s a ritual I look forward to. It’s finally spring so I can fertilise and up-pot. A good friend and I usually get our nails done every couple of months on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourite plant has spider mites. I had to buy her some special oil and insecticide and quarantine her. At the nail salon, the Vietnamese women made fun of my L’origine du monde pin. As many Viets, they don’t know that I’m Vietnamese and am fluent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So they said a bunch of nasty shit about me in Vietnamese (for you non-Vietnamese speakers, I’ll assure you this is rare; most salons are very kind and busy talking about other shit, not talking shit about you). I tried to focus on my friend but couldn’t. My stomach, tight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shit like this happens all the time. We all deal with people being rude. Most days, I brush off dozens of microaggressions and passive aggressive shit. I’m a Portland native. I was cultivated for temperate rain and passive aggressive shit. Move on, right? Well, I tried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depression is an oceanic undercurrent. I can be fine one moment, floating through my day and something will pull me under. Sometimes the force is strong and fast, other times it’s slow and nagging. Something about the combination of having to isolate my calathea hit me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am like my calathea. Isolated from where she was supposed to grow, a tropical sunny place, infested with this mildly harmful mite that isn’t an immediate threat, but it’s eating away at her very slowly. I am isolated from where I’m supposed to be too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a brown girl in a white world who isn’t American despite what my passport says. When I go to Vietnam, I’ll be an American girl in a Vietnamese world despite what my lineage says. So I don’t belong here nor there. I wouldn’t thrive there, just like I don’t here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have so much to be happy about, as friends and family remind me. And I am. I’m grateful for all my privileges. And I hurt. I have a lot to be sad about, too. I’m unfortunately capable of holding a lot—in my mind, in my heart, and in my soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s what I evolved to handle. My dual existence, or non-existence, is what gave me immense resilience. But it also made me acutely aware of everything around me. My heightened observational skills are survival mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when former colleagues criticised my sensitivity as a negative and undesirable work trait, it hurt. I have to be sensitive to survive. I can’t always turn it on or off, though I’ve gained the skills of hiding and showing it, for the most part. When I observe what I do, and others don’t believe me, it makes sense. Not everyone is forced to evolve in this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we’re all different plants, really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What gave me my light pink stripes, as if delicately painted by an Impressionist hand, and my dark green leaves, is also what made me susceptible to mites. What gives me my appearance gives me my pain. I isolated myself to not share my infestation, but then it leaves me alone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Monday Comms Tips</title>
		<link href="https://www.tatianamac.com/posts/monday-comms-tips/"/>
		<updated>2019-04-28T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.tatianamac.com/posts/monday-comms-tips/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I spent a lot of time in my inbox—I imagine many of you can relate. Over the years, I&#39;ve gathered some helpful communication tips that I found improved my efficiency and happiness. Balancing my email time for me is an exercise in automating the right things, while maintaining the humanness of communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;general&quot;&gt;General &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#general&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designate work time/admin time based on your energy/brain power. Now, I have a bit of a privilege here as I work independently. I answer emails on Monday, when I struggle to focus on deep-thinking work. I do deep work mid-week. I take intro/mentorship calls later on the week when I&#39;m wrapping deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only respond to most bulky emails on Monday. I have to set this boundary, or else I find myself distracted all week long. I get stuck in the email cog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re not obligated to tell someone all your free times. Protect your you time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Include pronouns in your email signature. If you&#39;re not sure of someone&#39;s pronouns, ask. Until you can ask, use gender neutral pronoun they/their/theirs and/or their name. Also be cognisant of accidentally outing people; always follow someone&#39;s lead and err on the side of uncertainty and asking 1:1 if you&#39;re unsure. If you mess up, apologise and fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop apologising for &#39;the delay.&#39; We&#39;re perpetuating this idea that people must respond within 24 hours. What a strain on our mental health, and what an unfair expectation to set upon everyone. If you must acknowledge the perceived delay, reframe as gratitude or regret: &amp;quot;Thank you for bearing with me as I worked on my response.&amp;quot; Or, &amp;quot;I regret it&#39;s taken me over a week to respond.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For bulkier emails, employ some information design. Create bulleted lists, bold action items. End emails with what you need to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Review your response to makes sure you answered all questions asked o f you. So many extra emails are caused by not reviewing the original email fully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;introductions&quot;&gt;Introductions &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#introductions&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For intros, always ask permission of both parties before reaching out. Consent, always.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provide context (websites/LinkedIn) and personal connection to encourage they do a bit of research and a clear reason you intro&#39;d them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Move the introducer to bcc: (with a note). Saves their inbox and lets them know you responded. As the introducer, remind folks &amp;quot;You can move me to bcc: when you respond.&lt;br&gt;
Include your pronouns when introducing yourself. &amp;quot;Nice to meet you all. I&#39;m Tatiana (I use she/they pronouns).&amp;quot; Set a precedence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;scheduling&quot;&gt;Scheduling &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#scheduling&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offer times early in an email thread that will end there. I find that preemptively offering times avoids the empty back and forth of &amp;quot;when are you available?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Include timezones.&lt;/em&gt; Use a tool like Spacetime to help you find amenable times without tying your brain into a knot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To confirm a time, send a calendar invite. (I also frame language in earlier comms, so it&#39;s not an unexpected invite, which is jarring. Include time zones and make sure your calendar time zone is set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offer non-call alternatives when appropriate. When someone suggests a call as a default, and it doesn&#39;t feel necessary, I usually suggest another non-call way to solve it. For example, sometimes starting a document with initial ideas, or reading through something, etc, is what is warranted. I&#39;ll include a line like, &amp;quot;If we both still feel a call would be necessary after this, happy to schedule a call with an agenda to make the most of both our time.&amp;quot; Despite being an ambivert, I find that calls drain me quite a bit. I also try to remind the other person that it&#39;s their time, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;scoping%2Fspeaking&quot;&gt;Scoping/Speaking &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#scoping%2Fspeaking&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save a list of questions and answers in your notes document. I find that I write the same questions and answers over and over, especially with scoping. Having a resource to copy and paste from is helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When writing those answers, make sure you clearly highlight things you need to customise. It can be offputting to receive form responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before asking a question, see if you can find it somewhere else, then confirm. For example, if you&#39;re about to ask someone their Twitter handle, try to do a preliminary search first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Protect your expertise.&lt;/em&gt; Many people will reach out to ask for free advice and not immediately offer budget, even when they have it. I am always here to support mentorship and provide free advice to community members, especially newer and underrepresented folks. However, where I draw the line if if someone is making money off of my expertise. Phrasing I&#39;ve found success with is, &amp;quot;I&#39;m so flattered by this request! While I am happy to offer help to not-for-profit, community-focused events, I do ask for a fee when working with for-profit organisations like yours. The fee is...&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maintain a spreadsheet with all your speaking events, with dates, honoraria, speaker bios, talk abstracts, and slide links. I promise it&#39;ll come in handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you get asked the same questions over and over for speaking/scoping, consider making a speaker bio and/or Frequently Asked Questions page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Leave Me To My Hard-Earned Joy</title>
		<link href="https://www.tatianamac.com/posts/joy/"/>
		<updated>2019-07-09T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.tatianamac.com/posts/joy/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s so incredibly hard for me to cultivate joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I successfully do it all the time. I find joy at the blistered 25,000th step in crooked Portuguese street, in the the song of languages I&#39;ve never heard before, in the shadow and stillness of the early morning light. I smile whenever someone chases after the bus and catches it, whenever a dog pees on its own leg, and when someone I love really, truly, hugs me in a way that makes it seem like our souls melted into one another. I fill at the textural :36 mark of &lt;em&gt;Perfect,&lt;/em&gt; at the sound of Gerhard Richter&#39;s palette knife, and of the tingling numbness when my glove makes contact with the bag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel self love when I set my mind to figuring out an entire developmental concept that was fuzzy at best, in a weekend, and dedicated myself to build something to prove it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it&#39;s not just the highfalutin shit, it&#39;s also the fucking brilliance of Veronica Mars (a show that tackled teenaged sexual assault head on), when my best friend and I get into laughing fits even though we&#39;re thousands of miles apart, and when I absolutely kill it with self-timer in a real Instagram influencer-style photo of my outfits in the middle of the goddamn street. My life is &lt;em&gt;blessed&lt;/em&gt; with so much joy, inspired by the art and the people whom I love with my entire being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even while I&#39;m able to experience joy in forms I&#39;ve always known and am just discovering, it does not mean that it is without tremendous effort. Depression has left me crying in the back corner of an Estonian palace and holding back tears in the middle of a pitch with Nike executives (Look past his head, I told myself, it&#39;ll dry out your eyes from the strain).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, there is systemic, institutionalised oppression. It is the weight I was born carrying, strengthened by the repetition, but never able to release myself from it. I carry it well. I try to accessorise around it. But the one catharsis I have is to acknowledge it. To say yes, this is here and something I have and always live with. They—they who experience it not—tell me that it doesn&#39;t exist, to ignore it (you know, to ignore the thing that does not exist), and that everyone carries a weight. And as I inhale to say the same four words, the leash snatches me back and I never exhale to speak those four words to explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, depression and oppression create a dangerous intersection that I cross thousands of times a day. For the most part I just work on not letting the cars hit me from both sides. But sometimes when I&#39;m looking up at that gorgeous chiaroscuro effect on that ugly ass highway overpass and I go to snap a photo, someone yells out of their car something assaulty or racist,  a powerful, retractable leash that I have no control over can snaps me back to them instantly, mid-smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 40 continuous minutes of Mike Posner, 33 mental images of the Fauves, the 12 kind and loving text messages you sent—they can&#39;t protect me anymore. Like feathers to the wind, the earth reinherits them. I can pick them up when the leash loosens, when the neck heals, but I am more tired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, dear friends, know this. When it seems like what I&#39;m saying is heavy, that I&#39;m being negative, that I never seem to stop fighting, or that I won&#39;t stay in situations that you didn&#39;t see anything wrong with, it&#39;s because of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have worked so incredibly hard for so much, but &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; in a quest to have and to hold my feathers of joy—walking against the wind—whitened knuckles. When you tell me to be more positive, it demonstrates that you cannot perceive the metric tonnes of positivity it took me to get exactly where I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you can&#39;t find room in your heart or in your mind to be curious about that, that&#39;s fine. But all I ask from you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me revel in the revelry, let me laugh at the quiet parts, let me find whatever narrow outlets that I can to plug in and to recharge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it&#39;s not just me. We might not understand each other. But that doesn&#39;t mean we can&#39;t let each other have room to understand ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should let people love each other, whomever that is, however that is. We should let people like things, so long as those things are not foundationally rooted in hate and harm. We should let people indulge in dessert before lunch and breakfast for dinner, making out under mountains and monuments, and dusk-til-dawn video game sessions—we should let people enjoy things—*especially, please—*for those of us for whom seeking and retaining joy is so fleeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote this post to the stunning album &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/4Ud6qdjOiGsrryFeZOVmkT&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Real Good Kid&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Mike Posner. Worth a listen &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; if you have 40 minutes to listen straight through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
